Excuse me, sir.
Yes, sir.
Have you ever been broke before?
No.
I don't know. I don't think so.
Yeah? And what do you, I gotta ask you, what
do you do for a living out here in Dallas, Texas?
Like what industry did you pursue a career in?
Uh, consulting.
Consulting? Quick question for you. I started a
channel in Austin, Texas, at the University of
Texas. I go all over the country. What I do for
a living is I just ask people a couple questions on
their best advice to the younger generation. Can I
just get two minutes of your time, one minute of
your time real quick?
This is legit.
I promise you, I'll show you the channel.
What was the most amount of money that you
ever made in a single year?
My businesses today make roughly 500 million a year.
About a billion.
Top line revenue of $40 million.
Eight to 10 million.
Did you come from a lot of money?
No.
I came from nothing.
You're sitting in a Rolls Royce right now. This
is a lot of people's dream car right here.
Yeah.
How can somebody get a Rolls Royce in 2024?
Dallas, Texas is one of the richest
cities in the entire world. And today,
I'm going to be going all over Dallas to
ask some of the wealthiest people in the entire city,
how they became wealthy and how you can
start your path to becoming financially free in 2020.
So with that being said, let's
get this video on the way.
Excuse me, sir. Question for you.
Have you ever been broke before?
Excuse me, sir. Question for you,
sir. Have you ever been broke before?
Nope.
Yeah? In what industry did you-
Guys, we're busy.
What do you do for
a living out here in Dallas?
We're busy, guys. Go ahead.
Excuse me, sir. Question for you.
Have you ever been broke before?
Have I been what?
Broke?
Yes, sir.
Man, dude, I live one foot on
banana peel, another foot on bankruptcy court.
Yeah?
Yeah.
What industry did you pursue a career in? What
do you do for a living out here in Dallas?
Mail stripping.
Excuse me, sir. Question for you.
Have you ever been broke before?
Been broke?
Yes, sir.
Fortunately, no.
No? And what do you do for
a living out here in Dallas, Texas?
I'm retired.
What did you do? What industry were you in?
I was in the professional services industry.
What were you doing exactly? Were you a business?
I was a business owner.
I was a partner in a big accounting firm.
Yeah? Question for you. I started the channel
in Austin, Texas. When I went to UT,
I grew up to 5 million followers
just asking business owners and entrepreneurs their best
advice to the younger generation. Could I get
just one minute of your time real quick?
I got to run.
No worries. Have a good day, sir.
Thank you, sir.
All right, you guys. So as you can see,
since we're in Dallas, one of the wealthiest cities
in the entire world, it is very hard to
get any access to these people for interview questions.
But all we can do is keep on going until
we find that yes and drop some amazing business game for
you guys. I'm not stopping until I deliver
you guys the best value and advice possible
next.
Let's go. Quick question for you.
Have you ever been broke before?
What?
I don't know. Let's define broke.
I guess where you struggle financially.
Yes.
Yeah?
Yeah, I have.
What industry did you decide to pursue a career in?
What do you do for living out here in Dallas,
Texas?
I run banks.
What was the most amount of money
that you ever made in a single year?
My businesses today make roughly 500 million a year.
How did you scale to a nine-figure business? A
lot of people, they have a great idea, they start.
Mostly through acquisition.
What do you implement to scale them, though?
The game in banking is to
buy them and strip out costs.
Right. So were you always in banking?
44 years, yeah.
How important was that focus and not diversify
and trying to jump from industry to industry? How
important was it for you to get really good at
one thing as opposed to trying to become a master of
many different industries?
It's pretty simple. I preach to people who want
to be entrepreneurs that the worst thing you can
have is plan B. Plan B is the largest enemy to
plan A. It takes away focus from plan A. If you're
already thinking about what you're going to do
if this doesn't work, you're already starting behind.
You've got to play like the only thing that's going
to work is plan A. Not everybody agrees with me,
but I think plan Bs are awful.
More than 90% of businesses actually won't make
it past five years. What's the most common mistake
you see business owners make that prevents them
from scaling and having that kind of longevity?
They don't understand cash flow. So a lot
of businesses will grow fast and think they're
successful and they outstrip their capital. And
when you outstrip your capital, it's hard to
recover. It's understanding the financial
side of the business is important.
There is a big debate about whether
people should borrow money to start businesses,
trying to go get loans or borrow capital from
banks. What's the best way to go about funding
and starting businesses in today's world?
Equity.
What do you break that down?
Investors.
Find investors. But there's a risk there as
well because then you're having to manage other people's
wants for your company now. Would you agree with that?
Or my belief is don't let any investor be too
big or otherwise you're working for them. I've had a
lot of guys who wanted to put a lot more
money behind me and I'm like, I'm not looking to work
for you. I just want you to invest. Yeah.
How old are you now?
I'm 67.
You look incredible for 67. What's
the secret to looking so young?
Oh, wow.
I aspire to look that way at 67.
Get to the gym every day and eat well.
Yeah, I can tell, man. I appreciate
you. With everything that you've learned throughout your
career, though, if there's one lesson,
like what advice would you give?
To your 20 year old self if
you were starting all starting over again?
Go out on my own sooner than I did.
You think everybody's built for entrepreneurship, though?
No, not everybody's built for it. But
if you want to make real money,
you usually have to make it work for yourself.
Thank you so much. I really appreciate you. Have
a great day. Actually, I got to get one more.
Okay.
Negotiation. It's a big component of businesses
and closing deals and your businesses have done
multiple nine figures. You're at the table with
some heavy hitters. What's your best sales and
negotiating advice for people trying to get better
at closing clients and closing deals in today's
world? Do you have a tactic for somebody that
maybe they're running an agency or a type of
business where they're trying to get a job?
To close people? What's your best negotiation
advice for people trying to close more deals?
Walk away. The best deals I've done in
my life, I've walked away and they've come back.
Thank you so much. I appreciate you. What's your name?
Good luck to you guys. Kevin.
Kevin James. Great to meet you, sir. I really
appreciate you. So my guy made over $500 million
by running banks throughout the state of Texas. But
what did he say is the most common mistake
businesses make in today's world? It's that
they don't understand cash flow. Remember this,
in any business you start, cash flow is king.
You can never starve your company or else you
go bankrupt and broke. Great interview out here
in Dallas, Texas, man. Let's get this next one.
Excuse me, sir. Have you ever been broke before?
I don't know. I don't think so.
Yeah. And what do I got to ask you?
What do you do for living out here in Dallas,
Texas? Like what industry did you pursue a career in?
Consulting.
Consulting. Quick question for you. I started a
channel in Austin, Texas, at the University of
Texas. I go all over the country. What I do for
a living is I just ask people a couple questions on
their best advice to the younger generation. Can I
just get two minutes of your time? One minute of
your time real quick. I promise you, I'll show
you the channel. It's called the School of Hard Knocks.
I've interviewed Mark Cuban, the president of
Nike, CEO of 7-Eleven. So you're a consultant.
I was. Retired.
What types of businesses did you consult for?
Frito-Lay, American Airlines, TXU
Energy. Large, medium, small.
What's the most common mistake you
see business owners make? Because most businesses,
they don't make it past five years. What's
the most common mistake you see business owners make
that prevents them from scaling? They
have a great product or service,
but they don't know how to manage cash flow.
What was the hardest skill that you had to
master as a consultant and as a business owner?
What was the-
Casting a vision for a team, small team, to make
it into a large team that this is where we are,
but this is where we're going. Follow
me. I'm going to get us there.
What was the most amount
of money you had to make?
The most amount of money that
you ever made in a single year?
Eight to 10 million.
Eight to $10 million. That's just for yourself?
That's not just the business, that's for yourself?
Yeah.
How did you scale your
income from seven to eight figures?
I obtained equity in our company. So I had
a salary, half a million. I had a bonus,
salary, 500,000, half a million, 250 bonus.
But the seven or eight million came through
dividends on the equity that we
owned because we were so profitable.
How old are you now?
59, almost 60.
Thank you so much for your time. So you
look amazing for 59, by the way. What advice would
you tell your 20-year-old self if you were
to go back to when you were starting over?
What would you tell your younger self?
Love what you do and you'll
never work a day in your life.
Yeah. Did you come from a lot of money?
I came from nothing.
How did you change your family's trajectory? What was
it that you did that motivated you to kind of-
Instead of working for a salary for the big man,
I'd learned my trade in 10 years working for the
big firms. And then the next 20,
25 years, I built my own companies.
You got amazing advice. Thank you so much.
All right.
Greatest lesson you learned about entrepreneurship?
Most fail, but you have to have the
burn the ships mentality. There is no retreat
and you're taking the island.
You got amazing advice. Thank you so much.
So my guy made from eight to $10 million
personal as a business.
So my guy made from eight
to $10 million personal as a business.
He's a consultant. Dallas, Texas has the moguls
out right now, guys. Great interview out here in
Dallas, man. Let's go get this next one. Come
on. Excuse me, sir. Question for you. Have you ever
owned a business?
Yeah.
What industry?
Restaurants.
So you own restaurants?
Yeah.
For how long?
Too damn long.
Restaurant business is very competitive. What did you
do to stand out? What did you do differently?
I bought a franchise so that somebody else would
do the heavy thinking. All I had to do
is run the restaurants.
What franchise?
Golden Chick.
He ran Fridays.
But I was running Fridays.
I was running Fridays.
TGI Fridays?
Yeah.
You were the CEO?
Yeah, I was.
That's incredible. Leadership's a big struggle with
a lot of companies in today's world.
Still is.
Where do most people go wrong, in your
opinion, when you're looking at organizations as a whole?
They don't build a team that
supports them, and they think they're king,
and they don't think the other people matter.
Across all of your businesses, in terms of
revenue, what was the biggest issue you ever had?
About a billion.
A billion dollars. As somebody who's sold
over a billion dollars throughout your career,
let me ask you this. What's the
best financial advice you've ever been given?
Don't rush into owning your own business
if you can work for the other guy.
What do you mean by that?
If you own your own business, you have to put
your house up, you have to put all your assets up,
and if you work for the other guy, you don't
have that risk. You just lose your job and get another
one.
Did you come from a lot of money growing up?
No.
What did your parents do?
Well, my dad was sickly. He really couldn't
work. My mother worked at a drugstore as a
counter clerk.
How old are you now?
I'm over 70.
Over 70. You look great for 70. Seriously.
Thank you.
I wouldn't have guessed that.
How important is it to choose the right
life partner? That's a big problem in today's world.
A lot of people, they marry the wrong
person, their life can go downhill. How important was
that to you?
Well, you got to have support at home.
If you go home and you're miserable and things
are not working in your way,
your work life will be crap. Sorry.
If you're just working the
work, then it's not worth it.
And your health will be crap.
How can somebody become a millionaire in 2024?
I go long on real
estate. Real estate never goes down.
Thank you so much for your time.
All right. Y'all have fun.
Thank you, sir.
You've got capital partners.
We watched it all and the
people who had money, really made money,
own the properties. Instead of leasing
and renting, they bought the land.
So own that and don't sell it.
Don't sell.
Hard Knocks family,
we're on our way to go get our next
interview right now, but I've got a very special announcement
to make. We just hit 1000 members in
our private entrepreneur community known as the School of
Mentors. And inside of this community, I'm hosting
live calls every single week with the multi
millionaires, the eight, nine, and even 10
figure entrepreneurs that I interview every single week
on this channel. I'm talking about people
that have built and sold billion dollar companies.
You'll be able to hop on these
calls and ask them questions about your career,
your life, and your businesses.
There's also exclusive content and masterclasses
filled inside of this community with the
most successful business owners for you to
live and grow. So if you're interested
in that, I'm happy to help you.
Learn from. So to join this community today,
click the link down in the description below,
because you do not want to miss out on
this opportunity. I can't wait to see on the inside
of the community. But with that being
said, let's get back to the interviews.
Excuse me, sir. Yeah. Is this your Rolls Royce? Yes.
And what do you do for living out here in
Dallas, Texas to be able to afford a Rolls
Royce? I'm an entrepreneur. Yeah. Yeah. How long have you
been a business owner for? 25 years after doing
eight years in Marines. You were in the Marine
Corps? Yes. And I guess over these 25 years
as a business owner, what has been the most amount
of money that you've ever made in a single
year? Top line revenue of $40 million. You said 40
million? 40 million. What's been the best
financial advice that you've ever received? Oh,
best financial advice? I mean, I'm in
financial services. I see all types of advice. I would
say the best thing for me was I was sitting
down with a Goldman Sachs guy and I said, when
can you flip my 10 million to 20 million? He said,
stop it. I know how you guys make money inside
the insurance industry. I know how much money you guys
make. Guys like you are my typical clients.
You're better off investing back into you. Invest back
into your own business. If you expect your money
to double, invest back into you. And what does
that mean though? Skills, associations,
relationships, reputation. That's what it means
to invest back into yourself. How old are you now?
I'm 50. How old were you when you became a
millionaire? I was, well,
the first time I did was in my thirties. Lost
it, bad relationship. And then I rebuilt it in my
forties. So you went broke. I went broke. Broke
two or three times. How did you kind of bounce
back from that? When you're in the worst
position, you're actually in the best position. That's when
God shows up and says, hey man, you want to answer
my call now? And so that's it. When God calls you,
man, when you're in the worst
position, because when everything's great, friends, money,
associations, you sometimes forget where your blessings
and your resources come from. But when
you're at the bottom, that's when God reminds us,
hey, you remember all this stuff came from? Guess
who it came from? It didn't come from you,
your skills, your talents, your abilities. It came from
your father in heaven. And when much is given,
much is expected. When you don't do anything with
it, you don't do much with the, with the, with
the lease that he's given you, you try to take credit
for it. That's when bad things start to happen.
Have you ever met a billionaire before? I have
actually, a company just bought us for $30 million
a couple of years ago. What do billionaires do
differently from everybody else? Two things. Number
one, they ask the most questions just
like you are. And then number two, they go
into a room not thinking that they know everything.
Ray Dalio said in his book, Principles, he said,
I go into rooms thinking I'm wrong just to be
proven that my position was actually correct
based on the debates and conversations happening. You're
sitting in a Rolls Royce right
now. This is a lot of people's
dream car right here. How can somebody get a
Rolls Royce in 2024? Well, a couple of things is
once the interest rates start kicking everybody's
tail, everybody had a fun, affordable lifestyle
two, three, four years ago, and they didn't save
money. They're selling it right now. 20, 30, 40,
50% discount. Watch any car dealership auction right
now. Watch these cars not being sold on
auction. These be purchased at a premium. Now
they're being purchased at a discount. When times
are good, be the guy that stacks cash. When
times are great, be the one that constantly puts money
away. Why do you think Apple and all
these companies have billions and billions of dollars
cash just sitting on the side?
Why? Because they're waiting for opportunities. If you want
to afford a Rolls Royce, I wish I could
say you could do it this year, but if you
stack cash, you make enough money this year and you're
stacking that cash away, someone's going to say,
hey Matt, can you unload this Mercedes off me?
Can you load this Rolls Royce off me? Can you
load this Bentley off me? I'm going through a bad
situation. I'm going through a divorce. I'm going
through a downsize in my business. And the only
asset that I have is this car. Can you pay me
cash for it? One time I had a guy say, hey Matt,
give me an offer for my vehicle and insult
me. Meaning he needed money right away. That's going
to happen right now during tough times if you are
the person that was wise to do with your money and
you saved cash. You got amazing advice,
sir. I appreciate it. Thank you so much.
That's a wrap on today's video guys. Dallas, Texas was
insane as always, but I want you to like and
subscribe for amazing content we've got coming very
soon. And as I mentioned earlier, our private
community, the School of Mentors just hit 1000 members.
So if you want to hop on live calls with
multimillionaires and billionaires and ask them
questions about how you can better yourself,
join with the link in the description of
this video. I can't wait to see on the
inside of the community. But with that being
said, we'll see you in the next video.